Vibrant and Whimsical!
One Man Band is a animation, comedy, family film directed by Mark Andrews.
With one coin to make a wish at the piazza fountain, a peasant girl encounters two competing
street performers who'd prefer the coin find its way into their tip jars.
The little girl, Tippy, is caught in the middle as a
musical duel ensues between the one-man-bands.
One Man Band is a 2005 Pixar animated musical comedy short film.
It debuted at the 29th Annecy International Animated Film Festival in Annecy, France, and
won the Platinum Grand Prize at the Future Film Festival in Bologna, Italy.
It was shown with the theatrical release of Cars.
It was written and directed by Andrew Jimenez and Mark Andrews and
produced by Osnat Shurer, head of Pixar's Shorts group.
The score was composed by Michael Giacchino.
Like many Pixar shorts, it is completely free of dialogue and vocal effects, instead
using music (played by the characters) and pantomime to tell the story.
Unlike most Pixar shorts, which are driven solely by storyboarding and scriptwriting, the music in One Man Band was developed
alongside the film's story; Giacchino collaborated extensively with the film's directors due to the music's large role.
On January 31, 2006, it was nominated for the Academy
Award for Best Animated Short Film.
It was included in the Animation Show of Shows in 2005.
The film explores themes of fountain, rivalry, coin, bag of money, little girl.
The tone is lighthearted.